Finding Aid for the The Donald Grady Davidson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- WRITINGS-POEMS
  - A Touch of Snow
  - A Trooper of Forrest
  - Twilight on Union Street
  - Two Landscapes
  - Vicisti, Leuconoe
  - The Vision
  - The Vow
  - Wassail! To Julia and John and Anne
  - The Way to Thorn
  - Who's Got... ?
  - Wild Game
  - Wilderness Meeting
  - Wind Chant for Autumn
  - Woodlands, 1956
  - X, Y, and Z
- Poems Untitled
  - Find me a shepherd who can say...
  - Sir, with not the slightest surprise...
  - Let now the brutal melodies...
  - Threading the maze that is myself...
  - When I left my old home...
  - The Angel proffered Apostle John...
- Poems Miscellaneous (includes untitled poems and fragments)
  - Prefatory Note
  - The Tall Men 1927 (frag.)
  - Lee in the Mountains and Other Poems, 1932-1938 (frag.)
  - The Return
  - A Little terrible...
  - From the Tomb of the Bishop
  - Let now the jaded melodies
  - Gnawing a little, day by day, somehow...
  - Under this hollow ice a soundless ocean...
  - Sing ah, for this bright thought...
  - Under the pulsing stars the lights swims free...
  - And you whose breath is but the dirty sneer...
  - Out of the sullen fury of the time...
  - Burning as if the summer wind had blown...
  - For this body give a soul...
  - Sir, with not the slightest surprise...
  - To the High Muck - le- Muck, with a bellows...
  - "The Season is dry, I said and promises yet no rain"
  - What solemn Incantation...
  - Closing the door, she first was softly ware
  - Close now the gate and lock the guardian tower...
- A Notebook--Notes for Poetry and Prose
  - Randall, My Son
  - The Bell Witch
  - The Hermitage
  - Your mother's folks were Huguenots,...
  - Traveler, haste, the time runs on
  - General Lee Remembers
  - Assembly at Murfreesbora
  - In the dark and green of water-oaks the fall of the cold spring rain
  - The Starlings
  - Guerillas
  - Meeting in Nashville
  - Country Roses, O
  - Summer in Vermont, Winter in Georgia -Prose
  - The Negroes-Prose
  - Emmett Blue and the "Passionate" Flower
  - Notes for Articles-Not Enough Cooks; Eastern Pilgrimage; Folklore; The Laughter of Time
  - The Journal- Questioni, Gennaio - Marzo, 1960
  - Lee Sulle Montagne
  - Una Pastorale Della Georgia: Randall, Figlio Mio
  - L'uomo Eccitabile (from Virginia Quarterly Review, Spring 1950)
  - Il Sud di un "Reazionario": Donald Davidson, an article by Claudio Gorlier
- DONALD DAVIDSON PAPERS
- APPENDIX B-- LITERARY CAREER-LIST OF CLIPPINGS ABOUT DAVIDSON'S WORK, 1924 - 1968
  - The Literary Review: ‘"The Literary Lobby, " by Kenel M. Digby., March 8, 1924
  - Record (Columbia, S.C.): "Rare Books of Poetry," a review of An Outland Piper., March 16, 1924
  - Nashville Banner: An Outland Piper, a review., March 16, 1924
  - The Lexington Herald, An Outland Piper, a review., March 23, 1924
  - The New York Times Book Review: "Poets Start Piping in This ‘Freshly Budded' Spring/ Six Volumes of Newly Published Verse," a review of An Outland Piper et al., March 30, 1924
  - Reading Sample: "New Poems/'An Outland Piper' "., April, 1924
  - Sigma Upsilon New Letter, Vol. III: An Outland Piper., April 1,1924
  - The Bookman: "Individual Verse," by David Morton, May 1924
  - Southern Magazine: "Dextrous Measures," An Outland Piper reviewed by Clyde Pettus., June 1924
  - The Stratford Monthly: a comment on Davidson's poems., June 1924
  - Nashville Tennessean: "A Page About Books.", Nov. 29,1924
  - The Dallas Morning News: "An Outland Piper by Donald Davidson Has Lyrical Passion," by Hilton R. Greer., Dec. 21, 1924
  - The Dallas Morning News: "The World of Letters/Ransom Comment on Books and Bookmen.", Feb.1, 1925
  - Sigma Upsilon News Letter: "Donald Davidson.", March 1, 1925
  - The Dallas Morning News: "Thirty-two Poetry Magazines Have Appeared Since The first one in 1912/ Each Section of the Country Now has its Representative/The General Interest in Poetry is Preparing the Way for a Great Poet, Masefield Says," By Isaac C. Wade and Ellen Lovell., April 12, 1925
  - New York World. "Advice to Shepherds.", July 4, 1926
  - Chattanooga News: "Dinner in Honor Donald Davidson Event of Tonight.", Nov. 27, 1926
  - Folder
  - Atlanta Georgian: "Writers Will Hear Vanderbilt Author.", April 21, 1927
  - Journal (Milwaukee, Wis.): citation of The Tall Men., Sept. 3, 1927
  - Nashville Tennessean: "Davidson's New Book Off Press.", Sept. 15, 1927
  - Nashville Banner: a citation of The Tall Men., Sept. 18, 1927
  - Transcript (Boston, Mass.): a citation of The Tall Men., Sept. 24, 1927
  - New York Publisher's Weekly: a citation of The Tall Men., Sept. 24, 1927
  - New York Herald Tribune: a citation of The Tall Men et al., Sept. 25, 1927
  - State (Columbia, S.C.): " The Tall Men by: Donald Davidson," review by J.V, N., Sept. 25, 1927
  - Nashville Banner: "The Tall Men.", Sept. 25, 1927
  - News (Lynchburg, Va.): a citation of The Tall Men et al., Sept. 25, 1927
  - Commercial Appeal (Memphis, TN): "I Reckon So," by T. H. Alexander., Sept. 26, 1927
  - Times (Raleigh, N. C.): "Tennesseans and Their Background in Lyric Poetry," by M. G. A., Oct. 1, 1927
  - Saturday Review of Literature (N.Y, N. Y.): a citation of The Tall Man (sic)., Oct. 1, 1927
  - N. Y. Times: a citation of The Tall Men., Oct. 2, 1927
  - Star (Indianapolis, Indiana): "Many Books of Verse Appear in Fall Output of Publishers.", Oct. 2, 1927
  - Nashville Tennessean: "Donald Davidson's New Volume Offers Poetry Singularly Sustained/ Fosters Question of Attitude Becoming Men of South in Present Circumstances," review of The Tall Men by John Crowe Ransom, Oct. 2, 1927
  - Nashville Tennessean: "The Tall Men, Donald Davidson's New Book Given Wide Praise/Publication Goes on Sale Here Today; Is Writer's Second Collection Of Poems.", Oct.4, 1927
  - Union (New Haven, Connecticut): review of Stygian Freight by Cale Young Rice, including a comment by Davidson., Oct. 7, 1927
  - Lake County Times (Hammond, Indiana): a citation of An Outland Piper., Oct. 8, 1927
  - Lender (Manchester, N. H.): a citation of The Tall Men., Oct. 8, 1927
  - News (Dayton, Ohio) :a citation of The Tall Men., Oct. 9, 1927
  - Sentinel (Knoxville, TN): "The Tall Men is Epic of Tennessee," a review of The Tall Me by R.E. McCormick., Oct. 9, 1927
  - Nashville Tennessean: "Communicatons," a letter by William Bandy., Oct. 9, 1927
  - Commercial Appeal: a citation of The Tall Men., Oct. 9, 1927
  - Times Picayune (New Orleans, La.): "Notable Books," a citation of The Tall Men., Oct. 9, 1927
  - Commerical Appeal: a newspaper illustration entitled, "The Tall Men/ Portrait Of a Tennessean.", Oct. 9, 1927
  - Union (Manchester, N. H.): a citation of The Tall Men., Oct. 10, 1927
  - Democrat (Johnstown, PA): a citation of The Tall Men., Oct. 10, 1927
  - Transcript (Boston, Mass.): a citation of The Tall Men., Oct. 15, 1927
  - Commercial Appeal (Memphis, TN): "Authors Will Meet at Tri-State Fair.", Oct. 16, 1927
  - Republican (Springfield, Mass.): a citation of The Tall Men, Oct. 23, 1927
  - Democratic Chronicle (Rochester, N. Y.): "New Era in South ", Oct. 23, 1927
  - Evening Post ( - --, S.C,): "To Address Poetry Society/ Donald Davidson Speaks on ‘Poetry and Progress' Friday Night.", Oct. 24, 1927
  - News and Courier (Charleston, S.C.): "Nashville Poet to Make Address/ Davidson to Be Speaker Before Poetry Society/ First Meeting Friday/ Begins Eighth Year of Existence with Full Membership.", Oct. 25, 1927
  - ?: " Poetry Society Meets Friday/Donald Davidson, Nashville, will Deliver Address.", Oct. 27,1927
  - Age Herald (Birmingham, Ala.): "I Reckon So," by T. H. Alexander, Oct. 27, 1927
  - News and Courier (Charleston, S. C.) "Tennessee Poet Speaks Tonight/ Donald Davidson Will Address First Meeting of Poetry Society.", Oct.28, 1927
  - News and Courier (Charleston, S.C.): "Poetry Society Hears Davidson/ Tennessee Poet Speaks, on ‘Poetry and Progress'/Art Begins with Life/Poet Cannot Retire to Ivory Tower, Lecturer Declares." Nov., 1927, Bookman (N.Y., N. Y.): a comment on Davidson. Nov. -Dec. 1927, Bozart (Atlanta, GA.): " Pasture on Parnassus," by Ernest Hartsock, A review of The Tall Men et al., Oct. 29, 1927
  - Observer (Baltimore, Md.): "A Goodly Peper/This," a citation of Tall Men (sic.), Nov. 5, 1927
  - Telegraph (Macon, GA.): a citation of The Tall Men., Nov. 6, 1927
  - Spokesman Review (Spokane, Washington): a citation of The Tall Men., Nov. 6, 1927
  - Folder
  - Christian Advocate: "Two New Books of Distinction/A Son of the Pioneers," By G. B. Winton, Nov. 11, 1927
  - New York Times Book Review: "Five True Poets and a Satirist/ New Books By John Hall Wheelock, Alfred Noyes, Humbert Wolfe, Donald Davidson, Evan Morgan and Leonard Bacon," by Percy Hutchison., Nov. 13, 1927
  - Call (Allentown, PA): a citation of The Tall Men., Nov. 13, 1927
  - Times (Asheville, N. C.): " A Tennessee Poet," a review of The Tall Men by Willis Posey., Nov. 13, 1927
  - Commercial Appeal (Memphis, TN): "Our Heritage/At Once a Tennessean's Pride and His Responsibility," a review of The Tall Men by John Crowe Ransom., Nov. 20, 1927
  - Journal of Commerce (Chicago, Ill.): a citation of The Tall Men, Nov. 26, 1927
  - Observer (Charlotte, N. C.): a citation of The Tall Men., Nov. 27, 1927
  - Journal Courier (Louisville, KY): a citation of The Tall Men., Nov. 27, 1927
  - Transcript (Boston, Mass.): a citation of The Tall Men., Nov. 30, 1927
  - Beacon News (Ill. ?): a citation of The Tall Men., Dec. 3, 1927
  - Saturday Review of Literature (N. Y., N. Y.): " Two Types of Poetry," A review by Stephen Vincent Benet of The Tall Men and Trinc by H. Phelps Putnam., Dec. 10, 1927
  - Nashville Tennessean: "Benet Suggests The Tall Men As Material Worthy Of Pulitzer Prize/ Noted Poet in Saturday Review Places Davidson In Class With Masters and Neihardt.", Dec. 14, 1927
  - Record (Columbia, S. C.): a citation of Davidson et al., Dec. 24, 1927
  - Express (San Antonio, Texas): "The Literary Lantern," a citation Of The Tall Men., Dec. 28, 1927
  - Desert News (Salt Lake City, Utah): "Books and Authors," a citation of The Tall Men., Dec. 28, 1927
  - Poetry: A Magazine of Verse: a review of The Tall Men by H. M., Jan. 1928
  - The Nation: " A Tennessee Epic," a review of The Tall Men by John Gould Fletcher., Jan. 18, 1928
  - Folder
  - Saturday Review of Literature (N. Y., N. Y.): "Books of Special Interest/ A Contrast in Poets, " Ballads of the singing Bowl by Marjorie Allen Seifert and The Close Chaplet by Laura Riding (Gottschalk), reviewed by William Rose Benet; Mentions Davidson., Feb. 11, 1928
  - Times-Union (Jacksonville, Fla.): "Poetry, Songs, and Ballads," a review Of The Tall Men., Feb. 12, 1928
  - Voices: The Pale Woman by Sara Bard Field and The Tall Men, reviewed by Oliver Jenkins., May 1928
  - Beacon-News, (Aurora, Ill.): a citation of Davidson, May 26, 1928
  - N.Y. Herald Tribune Books: "Turns With A Bookworm," a citation Of Davidson by I.M. P., July 15, 1928
  - Book Review Digest: a citation of Fugitives, an Anthology of Verse., Aug. 1928
  - Knoxville Journal: "To Welcome Donald Davidson.", Nov. 26, 1928
  - "Christmas in the Old South, " A Talk Made by Mr. Donald Davidson Of Vanderbilt University on the Caldwell radio program, Dec. 21, 1928
  - Caldwell and Co., Southern Securities, Nashville, TN, Dec. 21, 1928
  - Nashville Tennessean: an illustration from The Tree Named John, edited By Donald Davidson., Sept. 22, 1929
  - Times (Toledo, Ohio): a citation of The Tall Men. Missing Folders that have dates May 21, 1926 - March 1934-in Fugitives and Agrarians, Sept. 22, 1929
  - Folder
  - Yale News (New Haven, Conn.): "Donald Davidson, Southern Writer, Sees Rot in Yale Review Diagnosis of South's Progress.", March 30, 1931
  - Star (Clarksville, Tn.): " ‘South is Advancing,' Donald Davidson Says, Answering Yale Publication Story.", April 17, 1931
  - News (Greensboro, N. C.): "The Reviewing Shambles of New York.", May 11, 1931
  - Birmingham News (Ala.): "Liberalism As A Factor in the Southern Outlook.", March 1934
  - The Sheffield Standard (Sheffield, Alabama): "TVA Chiefs Ignor South, Davidson Claims/ Southerners Not Leaders in Exclusive Experiment/ Speaker Declares Area Not Inhabited by All Guinea Pigs.", May 11, 1934
  - Nashville Banner: " Donald Davidson Gives Illuminating Views in Essay.", July 7, 1935
  - The Birmingham News (Ala.): "The New South Talks a Rebellion.", April 16, 1937
  - News (Chattanooga, TN): "Books.", April 23, 1937
  - Herald Tribune (N. Y.): "An Anthology.", May 16, 1937
  - Constitution (Atlanta, GA): "A Shelf of Classics", June 27, 1937
  - Republican (Springfield, Mass.): "Southern Regionalism," by Edward N. Jenckes, review of I'll Take My Stand., March 5, 1938
  - News and Observer (Raleigh, N. C.): "Critical Regionalism," review Of The Attack on Levia than by Allen Tate., March 13, 1938
  - Sentinel (Winston-Salem, N. C.): "Imperialism of Sections New Theory," Review of I'll Take My Stand., March 13, 1938
  - Nashville Banner: "Searching Probes of Social Ills," The Attack on Leviathan, reviewed by Richmond Croom Beatty., March 19, 1938
  - Morning Herald (Durham, N. C.): review of The Attack on Leviathan., March 20, 1938
  - Journal (Knoxville, TN): "Mr. Davidson Sees His Facts Logically.", March 27, 1938
  - Advertiser (Montgomery, Ala.): "Regionalism vs. Sectionalism.", March 27, 1938
  - Enquirer (Cincinnati, Ohio): "Recent Arrivals at Cincinnati Book Stores," Citation of The Attack on Leviathan., March 31, 1938
  - The Nashville Tennessean: " A Conscientious Citizen Defines A Problem/ Donald Davidson Argues Case of Regionalism/ Nation Entering Great Period of Debate.", April 3, 1938
  - News (Savannah, GA): "Donald Davidson Scores Our National Uniformity/ The Attack on Leviathan Again Carries Forward the Banner of Agrarianism," review Of Attack on Leviathan, by J. P. Dyer., April 3, 1938
  - Sun (N. Y., N. Y.): "Regionalism," review of The Attack on Leviathan, By Clayton Hoagland., April 15, 1938
  - News (Birmingham, Ala.): " Mr. Davidson Asks If South Intends to Do Nothing," Review of The Attack on Leviathan by William C. Frierson., May 1, 1938
  - Daily Times (Chattanooga, TN): "Davidson Expounds Philosophy of Agrarianism in Book of Essays on Regionalism and Nationalism in U. S," review Of The Attack onLeviathan by Frank W. Prescott., May 8, 1938
  - Telegraph (Macon, GA): "Today's Book," review of The Attack on Leviathan. By Eugene Anderson., May 14, 1938
  - Press (Savannah, GA): no title, review of The Attack on Leviathan., June 25, 1938
  - Observer (Charlotte, N. C.): no title, review of The Attack on Leviathan., June 26, 1938
  - Folder
  - World News (Roanoke, VA): "Books to Own," review of The Attack On Leviathan by Hon. Francis Pickens Miller., July 3, 1938
  - Christian Science Monitor (Boston, Mass.): "Regionalism and the South," Review of The Attack on Leviathan by Horace Reynolds., July 6, 1938
  - Book of the Month: no title, citation of Lee in the Mountains., Oct. 1938
  - Nashville Tennessean: "City's Doom Implicit in Davidson's Poems/ Lee in the Mountains Has Brilliant Examples, New and Old, of Work of Vanderbilt Professor," review of Lee in the Mountains by John Tompson., Oct. 16, 1938
  - Sentinel (Winston-Salem, N.C.): "Poems Have Robust Style, " Lee in the Mountains and Other Poems, reviewed by Kathryn Ames., Oct. 16, 1938
  - Journal (Knoxville, TN): "Poetry.", Oct. 16, 1938
  - Transcript (Boston, Mass.): "A Nashville ‘Fugitive' Talks for Robert E. Lee/ Donald Davidson Shows Southern Poets are Still Not Reconciled," review by John Holmes., Oct. 19, 1938
  - Journal (Atlanta, Georgia): Lee in the Mountains, review., Oct. 30, 1938
  - Washington (D.C.) Star: Lee in the Mountains, review, Oct. 30, 1938
  - Chattanooga Times: " Donald Davidson's New Book of Poems Holds Particular Appeal for Tennesseans," review of Lee in the Mountains by Elizabeth C. Palmer., Nov. 20, 1938
  - News-Sentinel (Fort Wayne, Ind.): "Significant Verse," Lee in the Mountains And Other Poems, reviewed by Floyd Logan., Nov. 28, 1938
  - Richmond Times Dispatch (Richmond, Va.): "Donald Davidson and Abbie Evans Praised," Lee in the Mountains and The Bright North by Evans, reviewed by Coleman Resenberger., Nov. 1938
  - The Philadelphia Inquirer: no title, comment on Lee in the Mountains., Dec. 3, 1938
  - Constitution (Atlanta, Ga.): "Southern Poetry," comment on Lee in the Mountains., Dec. 4, 1938
  - Telegraph, (Macon, Ga.): "Today's Book," review of Lee in the Mountains., Dec. 25, 1938
  - The Commerical Appeal (Memphis, Tn): "New Book Affirms Genius of Southern Poet, Davidson," review of Lee in the Mountains by George Marion O'Donnell, Jan. 1, 1939
  - News (Birmingham, Ala.): "Donald Davidson is Author of Volume of Fine Poems," Review of Lee in the Mountains and Other Poems, by William C. Frierson., Jan. 8, 1939
  - Herald Tribune (N. Y, N. Y.): Lee in the Mountains and Other Poems, reviewed By John Berryman., Jan. 8, 1939
  - Columbia Missourian: "Southern Poet/Donald Davidson's Verses of Civil War South Penetrating," review of Lee in the Mountains by Ward Allison Dorrance., Jan. 14, 1939
  - Observer (Raleigh, N. C.): "Davidson's Poems.", Feb. 5, 1939
  - Republican (Springfield, Mass.): Lee in the Mountains, review by A.M. J., Feb. 12, 1939
  - Birmingham Age Herald: "This Morning," by John Temple Graves, II; comment On I'll Take My Stand and on Vanderbilt University and O.C. Carmichael., March 10, 1939
  - New York Times Book Review: "About Old Ghosts and Tennessee Earth," review Of Lee in the Mountains by Peter Monro Jack., March 19, 1939
  - The Atlanta Journal: "Dixie Dominates Literary Field, Donald Davidson Says Here," by Adolph Rosenberg., March 24, 1939
  - Daily Times (Chattanooga, TN): "Roaming/ A.A.U.W.-Thomas Wolfe-- Edgar Allan Poe.", April 23, 1939
  - Folder
  - Times (Chattanooga, TN): no title, comment on The Tennessee., Aug. 11, 1940
  - Waterways Journal (St. Louis, Mo.): "News of River Books/ Nashville Author Now Writing a Tennessee River Book.", May 23, 1942
  - Times (Los Angeles, Cal.): "Story of Tennessee River Recalls Era of Pioneering," review of The Tennessee, Vol 1, by P.J. S., Nov. 17, 1944
  - News, (Newark, N.J.): The Tennessee, comment, Nov. 26, 1944
  - Observer(Charlotte, N.C.): "The Southern Scene.", Sept. 26, 1946
  - Journal (Knoxville, TN): "Vanderbilt Member to Address Historical Society Friday.", Sept. 29, 1946
  - Retail Bookseller: "The Tennessee, Vol. 1," citation., Oct., 1946
  - Herald (Boston, Mass.): no title; photograph of Theresa S. Davidson's Woodcut on the cover (bookjacket) of The Tennessee., Oct. 14, 1946
  - Sun (Chicago, Ill.): "I've Been Reading," by John T. Frederick (The Old Tennessee River")., Oct. 20, 1946
  - Sun (N.Y., N. Y.): "The Reviews: The Earlier History of the Tennessee: A Stirring Tale of the Scottish Border," by Clayton Hoagland., Oct. 23, 1946
  - same as Oct. 23, plus a photograph of Donald Davidson., Oct. 25, 1946
  - Journal (Milwaukee, Wis.): no title; review of The Tennessee, by E.C. Kiessling., Oct. 27, 1946
  - Herald Tribune, (N. Y., N. Y.): "The Tennessee Before TVA/Before Man Curbed the Wild River of the Cherokees," reviewed by Avery Craven., Oct. 27, 1946
  - Tribune, (Chicago, Ill.): "Past Brought Near in Book of Tennessee," The Tennessee, Vol. I, reviewed by Walter Havinghurst., Oct. 27, 1946
  - News (Chicago, Ill.): "The Tennessee Too Good to Cut," review of Vol.1., Oct. 30, 1946
  - Waterways, "News of River Books," review of Vol.I, by D. T. W., Oct. 31, 1946
  - Vanderbilt Alumnus (Vol. 32, No. 1): " Donald Davidson/ The Tennessee, Before T.V.A.," reprint of review by Avery Craven in N.Y. Herald Tribune Weekly Book Review, 10-27-46., Oct.- Nov.1946
  - The Knoxville News Sentinel: "Books Old and New," by Lucy Curtis Templeton Review of The Tennessee, Vol. I)., Nov. 3, 1946
  - State (Columbia, S. C.): no title, review of The Tennessee by Alderman Duncan., Nov. 3, 1946
  - Times (Hartford, Ct.): "Dramatic History of River Pageant Vividedly Recalled.", Nov. 9, 1946
  - Gazette (Little Rock, Arkansas.): "Books and History Recounted," by S.D. Dickinson., Nov. 10, 1946
  - Times Star (Cincinnati, Ohio): no title: review of The Tennessee, Vol. I., Nov. 17, 1946
  - Los Angeles Times: "Story of Tennessee River Recalls Era of Pioneering, Review of The Tennessee, Vol. I, by P. J. S., Nov. 17, 1946
  - Christian Science Monitor: "River of the Cherokees," review of The Tennessee By Horace Reynolds., Nov. 20, 1946
  - The Nashville Banner, "The Tennessee: The Old River: Frontier to Secession," Reviewed by Mary Stahlman Douglas., Nov. 20, 1946
  - Contra Costa Labor Journal (Richmond, Cal.): no title; review of The Tennessee, The Old River.. ., by Al Sessions., Nov. 22, 1946
  - Californian (Bakersfield, California): no title; review of The Tennessee, Vol. I., Nov. 23, 1946
  - Picayune (New Orleans, La.): "Distinguished Addition.", Nov. 24, 1946
  - Folder
  - Book of the Month Club: review of The Tennessee, Vol. I by George Genzmer., Dec. 1946
  - Guidepost: review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1., Dec. 1946
  - Chicago Tribune: "History and Biography Are Good in 1946," by Avery Craven., Dec. 1, 1946
  - Chronicle (Augusta, GA.): review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1, by Helen Colburn., Dec. 1, 1946
  - Journal (Milwaukee, Wisconsin) review of The Tennessee, Vol.1., Dec. 1, 1946
  - New York Herald Tribune: review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1., Dec. 1, 1946
  - Chicago Tribune: review of The Tennessee, Dec. 1, 1946
  - Traveler (Boston, Mass.): "Work Tells Story of the Tennessee," review by F.L.B., Dec. 2, 1946
  - New York Times: "History-Laden River," review of The Tennessee, Vol.1, By Harry Harrison Kroll., Dec. 8, 1946
  - Journal (Providence, R. I.): "New Course of ‘Rivers," review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1, by William E. Wilson., Dec. 8, 1946
  - Mercury Herald (San Jose, Cal.): "River's Story," review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1., by Gladys Hoover., Dec. 15, 1946
  - News (Charleston, S. C.): review of The Tennessee, Vol. By K. R., Dec. 15, 1946
  - St. Louis Post-Dispatch: " Time and the Tennessee," review by Rufus Terral., Dec. 19, 1946
  - Times-Herald (Dallas, Texas): "History of Two Rivers in One Bed," review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1, by W. Strickland., Dec. 22, 1946
  - News (Charleston, S. C.): review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1., by K. R., Dec. 22, 1946
  - World in Books (Boston, Mass.): review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1 by A.H. Scouten., Jan. 1947
  - Advertiser (Montgomery, Ala.): "Distinquised and Entertaining Story of Early Tennessee River is Grand," review of The Tennessee, Vol.1 by Ray Gould., Feb. 9, 1947
  - The Bookmark (Albany, N. Y.): review of The Tennessee, Vol. 1., March 1947
  - Christian Science Monitor (Boston, Mass.): " A New and An Old River Flow as One.", April 28, 1947
  - Christian Science Monitor (Boston, Mass.): "Flatboats on theTennessee.", July 31, 1947
  - New York Times: citation of The Tennesse, Vol. II., Dec. 15, 1947
  - RetailBookseller (N.Y.,N. Y.):citation of The Tennessee, Vol. II., Jan. 1948
  - Bulletin (Phila., Pa.): "On a River from Civil War to T.V.A.," reviewed by Leigh Mitchell Hodges., Jan. 18, 1948
  - Times (Chattanooga, TN): " Agrarian Davidson Shies at Progress," review Of The Tennessee, Vol.II, by James Livingood., Jan. 20, 1948
  - Herald Tribune (N. Y., N. Y.): "Books Out Today.", Jan. 22, 1948
  - Publisher's Weekly (N. Y., N. Y.): citation of The Tennessee, Vol. II., Jan. 24, 1948
  - The New Yorker: review of The Tennessee., Jan. 24, 1948
  - Plain Dealer (Cleveland, Ohio): "Tennessee Story Told in American Rivers Chronicles," review of The Tennessee, Vols. I and II by George J. Barmann., Jan.25, 1948
  - N. Y. Herald Tribune Weekly Book Review: "The Tennessee, Vol. II: The New River: Civil War to T. V. A.," reviewed by Gerald W. Johnson., Jan. 25, 1948
  - Folder